

Silam Pawar



87/33 Jeffcott Street, West Melbourne, VIC 3003



0470 322 579



Silampawar@gmail.com

Birthday: 04th Oct 1987 Languages: English

SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Java
- React JS
- Node IS
- MS SQL
- Estimations
- Technology Consultant
- Agile methodology

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

Bachelor of Technology 2005 – 2009
Computer Science

Higher Secondary 2004 – 2005
University of Mumbai

• SSC, Matriculate: 2002 – 2003

REFERENCES

Available Upon Request

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly accomplished and 8+ years experienced Java Developer with comprehensive mastery of Java and JSP. Expert at technical consultancy and project estimations. Able to work independently with little to no supervision as well as functioning as an excellent team player. The love for the technology is beyond the professional life which has encouraged me to leverage my knowledge to latest technologies like React JS and Node JS.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Solution design
- Development
- Technology Consultant
- Project Estimator
- Team Leadership

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Technology Consultant and Project Estimation ANZ Bank (via Infosys), Melbourne VIC

May 2012 - Present

Project Introduction: The Internet Banking website of ANZ bank is developed and maintained by Infosys. The project Internet Banking Solution Center has been providing quality solution and support to the web application for more than 10 years now.

Roles and responsibilities:

- Design and Developed the most complex payment solution New Payment Platform (NPP) for ANZ Bank.
- Have been involved in the NPP solution design and cost estimation since 2014.
- Have also acted as a technology lead for multiple releases.
- Currently involved in the Agile squad to design and develop REST services to expose payment functionality to the third party mobile application.
- Also providing technology consultation for the Enterprise Server Upgrade project which is uplifting software and hardware of the web application.
- So far have received 4 best performer of the quarter awards and many client appreciations for the timely delivery of the releases.

Java Developer

Emerson (via Infosys), India

May 2011 - May 2012

Project Introduction: Project involved the development of Migration Utility which assists Emerson Professional Services group in migrating Avocent customers from existing Data Center Management systems (namely Aperture VISTA, Avocent Data Center Planner and Liebert SiteScan) to Emerson-Avocent's Datacenter Infrastructure Management (DCIM) i.e. TRELLIS system.

Roles and responsibilities:

- Design and development of the multiple modules.
- Also contributed as a requirement analyst.
- Client communication and presenting showcases.
- Unite Test Planning

Junior Java Developer IBM Cognos (via Infosys), India

Dec 2009 - May 2011

Project Introduction: IBM Cognos is a Business Intelligence tool used by many clients in the world. Infosys provided the support and maintained the older versions

Roles and responsibilities:

- Design and development of the multiple modules.
- Bug fixing and performing unit testing.

Apart from above professional experience, I enjoy coding and developing small web applications in React JS, Redux and Node JS. Currently I am working on an Authentication module which enables user to login to the web application and requires authorization to access certain pages. To achieve this I have used JWT for token mechanism, Bcrypt to encrypt/de-crypt passwords and Passport library to manage login strategies.